Irina Rudenko

Child Psychologist, Ph.D.

PROFILE

Research and practical work with children and adolescents aimed at revealing and reaching their individual potential, supporting child's efforts in navigating the Self, setting and achieving personal goals, forming and strengthening self-confidence in the diverse life situations.

Areas of Interest

- Personality Development
- ► Child-Parents Relationships
- ► Psychological Assessment
- ► Career / Education guidance

Areas of Application

- ▶ Research work
- Consulting
- Science communication on child development topics

WORK EXPERIENCE

Since 2016: Consultant

Private practice, child development issues.

2008-2015: Career consultant

Career and education guidance (adolescents/adults), "Private Consulting Group",

Moscow, Russia

2006-2008: HR specialist,

Staff assessment and development, Lebedev Institute of Precision Mechanics and

Computer Engineering, Moscow, Russia

2003-2006: School psychologist

Private school «Personality», Moscow, Russia

1997-2001: Contributing Editor

"Family and School. The Magazine for Parents", Moscow, Russia

1993-1997: Child Psychologist

Centre for Disabled Children Rehabilitation, Moscow, Russia

1989-1993: Child Psychologist

Child Development and Family Therapy Center, Moscow, Russia

1987-1989: Researcher

Psychological Institute of the Russian Academy of Education, Moscow, Russia

EDUCATION

1983-1987: PhD

Moscow State University, Moscow, Russia

Field of study: Psychology

1978-1983: Diploma Degree (M.Sc. equivalent)

Moscow State University, Moscow, Russia

Field of study: Psychology

PUBLICATIONS

Doctoral Thesis: Interpersonal interaction style and its determinants. Moscow State University, 1988

Selected Publications in "Family and School. Popular Psychology Magazine for Parents":

"The Discreet Charm of Virtual Reality". How video games influence children. February, 1998

"The Legend of Tamagotchi". On the attachment to the virtual pets. March, 1998

"The Age of Doctor Spock." On Dr. Spock"s contribution to the modern views on child nurture. June, 1998

"Magic Beverage". Adolescents and alcohol. February, 1999

"Trip in a Schoolyard". On the problem of victims and bullies at school. March, 1999

"Grades and Marks". How school grades influence children. November, 1999

"Drawing means speaking". Early childhood drawings. January-February, 2001

"Schooling is a hard work". On the difficulties of the first school years. March, 2001

"Those important discoveries". Infants' first experiences. April, 2001

"Do toddlers need peers?". On the first communications of children. May, 2001

"Time to Speak". How children are learning to speak. June, 2001

"The right to private property". On the value of favourite toys. July-August, 2001.

"Blending magical and logical thinking". Preschoolers fantasies. September, 2001.

"They won't remember? Not quite!". On the infants memories. October, 2001.

"Shyness as a special attitude to life". What's the strength of timidity? November-December, 2001.

"7 questions to Family and School". Regular column featuring parents' questions on child development issues. 1997-1999

"From Scientific Mosaic. Facts, Arguments, Hypothesis". Regular column on the recent research advancements in child psychology. 1997-1999